Okay, so let's discuss one more earned
value term called TCPI, right?
TCPI means to complete performance index.
Alright, so TCPI then, two complete
performance index.
Now there's actually two formulas for
TCPI, and I'm going to discuss those
formulas on the next slide here,
but on this slide, I just want to explain
what TCPI actually means, right to
complete performance index right now i
mean the official explanation is basically
it's a rate of cost efficiency we need to
achieve in order to meet the budget all
right what rate of performance we need to
work at from a cost perspective what cost
efficiency we need to achieve in order to
meet the original budget all right so let
me explain that in English what does that
actually mean so let me just give you a
very simple but an extreme example right
to to explain this now
TCPI essentially means
work remaining divided
by budget remaining.
Now this isn't the formula, this is an
explanation.
There's two formulas for TCPI.
We'll talk about both of those two
formulas and the next slide.
But essentially the explanation is it's
work remaining divided by budget remaining.
So let me just give you a very simple,
but an extreme example.
All right?
So let's say we're in a
situation where we have
$100,000 worth of work
left to do on our project.
We have $100,000 worth of work left to do.
But we have $50,000 left in the budget.
So just a very simple question to you,
guys.
Is this a good or a bad situation?
If we have $100,000 worth of work left to
do and $50,000 left in our budget,
Is that good or bad situation,
right?
I think everyone will agree that that's a
terrible situation, right?
That's a really bad situation.
And that's basically what TCPI is
referring to.
What rate performance now do we need to
work at?
Right, so work remaining then,
we have $100,000 worth of work left to do.
Our work remaining is $100,000,
right?
Budget remaining, there's $50,000 left in
our budget.
Budget remaining is $50,000, so TCPI is
two, right?
or if it's expressed as a percentage,
200%.
So what does that mean?
It means if we want to meet our original
budget, right, there's only $50,000 left,
if we want to meet
that original budget, we
have to work at double
our cost efficiency.
We have to find a cost efficiency of 200%
in order to meet the original budget.
Are we going to find that?
No, well, most probably no.
Basically, looks like we're
going to be overbursed,
budget looks like we're
going to be way over budget.
So that's what TCPI is to complete
performance index.
What cost efficiency we need to achieve
between now and the end of the project.
So if we need to work at a rate of 200% or
find a cost efficiency of 200% between now
and the end of the project, then,
you know, that's really pushing.
Oh, you know, we could think it's almost
impossible.
I mean, not impossible.
It may happen.
but very, very, very unlikely.
It looks like we're going to be way over
budget.
Now, welfare was the other way around.
We have $50,000 worth of work left to do
and $100,000 left in our budget.
Right, then our TCPI is 0.5 or 50%.
We only need to work at a rate of 50% or
rather, we only need to find a cost
efficiency of 50% and we'll soon meet our
original budget.
So in other words, we're going to come in
under budget.
right?
I mean, you're not going to tell your team
though.
I'm not going to tell your teams to start
wasting more raw materials.
Right, no, I mean, you're
going to work at the same
rate, and then you're going
to come in under budget.
And that's what TCPI is, what rate
performance we need to work at.
Now, the examples I gave were, obviously,
these two examples are
very extreme examples.
But a TCPI of one is what you're
expecting.
Right?
To complete performance
index, you need to work
at a rate of 100% for
the rest of the project.
That means you're right on budget.
what we're expecting right if your tcpi
was less than one right let's say you have
a tcpi of tcpi of 0.98 you need to now
work at a rate of 98% for the rest of the
project so it means we're slightly under
budget right slightly better than what
we're expecting or if we have a tcpi of
1.02 now we need to work at a rate of 102%
for the rest of the project so just
showing that we're slightly over budget
there might not be the
end of the world but you
know we need to to find
some efficiencies, right?
Looks like we're going to be a little over
budget.
All right, so in our example then, the
example that we've been using, right?
We've got two TCPI formulas, right?
So the first TCPI formula is BAC minus EV
divided by BAC minus AC.
So BAC minus EV, original budget minus our
earned value.
Original budget minus what we've
accomplished so far.
That's how we work remaining.
divided by original budget minus what
we've spent so far that's our budget
remaining and then the second TCPI
formally are just replacing the second BAC
with EAC right now remember what does TCPI
mean it means what cost efficiency we need
to work at to achieve now the first one is
to meet our original budget the second one
is to meet our forecasted budget because
you're using the EAC there in both cases
it's looking at what rate of cost
efficiency we need to work at right in
order to meet then the first one is the
original budget second one is a forecasted
budget right all right so in our example
here right and the example that we've been
using original budget BAC is 100,000 right
EV that we calculated in a prior video
40,000 an actual cost that also is given
to us in the question 60,000 plug the
numbers in and you get 1.5 What is that
telling us?
That's saying that
between now and the end of
the project, we need to
work at a rate of 150%.
Cost-wise, we need
to find a cost efficiency
of 150% between now
and the end of the project.
So it looks like we're going to be over
budget.
Now notice the two other indexes that we
talked about, or two other indices,
CPI and SPI.
CPI and SPI are looking at what rate of
performance we've worked at so far,
TCPI is looking at the cost efficiency
going forward.
And TCPI is directly related to CPI.
CPI's cost performance index, the rate of
cost efficiency we've achieved so far.
And so TCPI is looking at the rate of cost
efficiency we need to achieve.
So there is a direct but inverse
relationship.
So if CPI is less than one, then TCPI will
be greater than one, as in this case.
Now, the second TCPI formula then,
right?
So if we were using our ESE, again,
of the 120,000, the budgeted rate one,
then I will plug the form,
plug the numbers into
the formula, and in this
case, TCPI will be one.
Right.
So if we work at 100% rate for the rest of
the project, right, then, you know,
we will meet the, I mean, the,
the forecasted budget of 120,000.
So, you use the first TCPI formula when
the original budget is achievable,
use the second one when the original
budget is not achievable.
And in the exam, they usually,
I mean, they will tell you explicitly
whether the original budget is achievable
or not achievable.
If they don't tell you, the default is
always going to be the first one.
You always compare
to the original budget, so
the default is always
going to be the first one.
Okay.